conservatives.com 2014-10-28

# Privacy

This is a privacy policy for the Conservative Party website. Our homepage on the Web is located at [http://www.conservatives.com](http://www.conservatives.com/).

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by mail at the following address:

Conservative Campaign Headquarters  
4 Matthew Parker Street, London, SW1H 9HQ

You may contact us by e-mail at [webmaster@conservatives.com](mailto:webmaster@conservatives.com). 

You may call us at +44 (0) 20 7222 9000.

## Data Collection and Use

The Conservative Party strives to meet 'P3P' standards (the 'Platform for Privacy Preferences Project') on data privacy. We are the sole owner of any information we collect. We never sell, share, or rent this information unless we first disclose the fact in this privacy statement. We collect data in nine different ways.

### Site Registration

We collect your name and contact information (including postal & email address). At your option, we may also collect your gender and date of birth. This information is used for site customisation and contacting visitors (you may opt out of this usage). This data will be used by ourselves and our agents.

### Stay Informed

We ask for your name, postcode and email address if you subscribe to our email newsletters. We use this information to contact you about conservatives.com and let you know what Conservatives are doing up and down the country.

### Join and Donate

In addition to the information from site registration we need additional information if you wish to donate money or join. This includes payment information (such as your credit card number and expiry date) and personal information that we must collect to abide by legal and voluntary codes of conduct (such as the constituency in which you are registered to vote). This information may be used for user analysis, user-profiling and contacting visitors.

If you donate more than £7,500 to the Party via the website, we are obliged under the Political Parties Elections and Referendums Act 2000 to report such a donation to the Electoral Commission, who will publish the fact that you have made a donation over £7,500. For more information, please see <http://www.electoralcommission.gov.uk/>

Under the Political Party Elections and Referendums Act 2000 (PPERA) you must be on the electoral register in the UK excluding the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man in order to make a donation of more than £500.

### Volunteer

We collect your postal address and volunteering preference. This information will be used by ourselves and your local Conservative Association.

### Send to a Friend

If you choose, we can tell a friend about our site - or even a particular page if you prefer. To do this, we need to ask for your friend's name and email address. We shall send your friend a single email inviting them to visit the site or page you chose. We do not retain this information. Your Internet Protocol (IP) address will be included in the email headers so that the originator of the message can be identified if necessary by the recipient.

### Feedback and Comments

To send us a message using our feedback forms we collect your name, email address and comments. At your option we may also collect your postal code. This data will be used by ourselves and our agents for contacting you.

### Online Polls and Q&A Informational Sites

The Party, from time to time, hosts Online Surveys and Question and Answer (Q&A) Informational Sites on our website. The data you provide in response to questions asked on these sites will be retained by the Party in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998 and related legislation. We will use the data you provide to: 

a) improve our understanding of political life in the United Kingdom; 

b) compile and provide anonymous statistics about voters in the United Kingdom; 

c) facilitate our operation as a political party; and

d) help the Party in developing policies to include in manifestos for elections. 

For Q&A Informational Sites we will also use your responses to provide you with tailored information on the relevant subject area.

In addition we may also ask you for your contact details such as your email address. By entering your contact details you agree to receive communications from us, from which you can opt-out using the “unsubscribe” link in each email we send or using the contact details at the top of this privacy notice. We will not share your details with anyone outside the Conservative Party.   In addition we may use your responses in the survey to keep you informed about issues that matter to you.

If you wish to participate in an Online Survey, or make use of a Q&A Informational Site, in addition to your answers, we collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This data will be used to help validate the results and help prevent multiple entries from individuals. In addition to this a cookie will be placed on your system after participating in an Online Survey or Q&A Informational Site. No identifiable information will be stored in this cookie. If you wish to participate in an an Online Survey or Q&A Informational Site, in addition to your answers, we collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This data will be used by ourselves and our agents to help validate the results and help prevent multiple entries from individuals. In addition to this a cookie will be placed on your system after participating in a poll or survey. No identifiable information will be stored in this cookie.

### Log Files and Statistics

We use IP addresses, URI's of requested resources, timestamps and HTTP user-agents to analyse trends, administer the system and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. In addition to this we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies, to help analyse how visitors use our site. The information generated by the cookie about the use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our website, compiling reports on website activity for the Conservative Party and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your Web browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to make full use of our website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

## Cookies

Please visit our cookies page for information on what cookies this site uses.

## Web beacons and tracking links

 The Conservative Party uses Web beacons (also known as pixel tags and clean GIFs).  These involve graphics that are not apparent to the user, and which do not provide us with any data about individuals. Tracking links and/or similar technologies consist of a few lines of programming code and can be embedded in our websites. In conjunction with cookies, these are primarily used for statistical analysis purposes. This technology can also be used for tracking traffic patterns on websites, as well as finding out if an e-mail has been received and opened and to see if there has been any response.

  Our website provides Social Plug-ins of Facebook.com. When you visit one of our sites with Social Plug-ins (recognizable by a white F on a blue tile or a thumb up sign) your browser establishes a direct connection to the servers of Facebook. The content of the Plug-in will be transferred to your browser and implemented into the website. The information that you visit our website is now transferred to Facebook. If you are logged on in Facebook during the visit on our website, Facebook adds this information to your Facebook profile. If you are interacting with one of the Social Plug-ins, e.g. make a comment, this information will also be transferred to Facebook. In addition, other personal information as your IP address, Browser and other parameter may be transferred to Facebook and stored there.

  In case you do not wish such a data transfer, please log off in Facebook before you enter our website.

  We cannot influence this data collection and data transfer by the Facebook Plug-ins. Please see Facebook’s privacy statements for more information on the purpose and extent of data collection by Facebook, as well as how they further process and use your data there, and your related rights and setting options for protecting your privacy: (http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php).More information is also available at www.youronlinechoices.eu

## Links

Our website links to other sites, but we shall always try to warn you when this is the case. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites: make sure you read their privacy statements if you are concerned about the information they are collecting about you. This statement only applies to our website.

## Security

We take every precaution to protect your details. When you submit sensitive information via the website, it is secure both on its way to us and once we receive it. For instance, our membership and donation forms encrypt your credit card number using SSL encryption technology.

We also do everything in our power to protect your information once we have received it. Our staff can only access your details if they have a specific job to perform, such as dealing with a membership enquiry. They also have to keep up to date on our security and privacy practices.

Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

## Transfer of your information outside the European Union

As part of the services offered to you through our site, the information you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA"). By way of example, this may happen if one of our service providers is located in a country outside of the EEA. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the EEA. If we transfer your information outside of the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected and used only in accordance with our instructions and for the purposes we have indicated to you at the time of collection of the data.

## Supplementing Information

We take our responsibilities to protect you from fraud very seriously. To fulfil this obligation, we sometimes have to supplement the information you give us with information from third party sources - usually, in order to make sure that no-one else is using your credit card. We do not keep this information any longer than we have to.

## Correcting/Updating Information

We recognise that details such as your post code or email address are bound to change over time. We will do what we can to ensure that you can change the information we hold about you.

## Opting out/Unsubscribing

If you have signed up for emails from the Conservative Party but want to stop us getting in touch, you can opt out by following the "unsubscribe" instructions at the foot of every email we send.

## Notification of Changes

If we change our privacy policy, we shall post a link to those changes on our homepage so that you always know what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

When we collect information from you, we tell you what we intend to do with it; if we later want to use that information for a different purpose, we shall first send you an email setting out our plans - and it will be up to you whether or not we do so.
